# 小狗
Doggy!
# 大家好 今天帶大家去看一下我們家的小豬
Hi everyone! Today, we're gonna take you guys to see our piggies.
# 好久都沒看 過完 過完年到現在都沒看過
I haven't seen them, haven't seen them for a long time, since, since the Chinese New Year.
# 這全部都搬到兄弟家這邊來啦
They have all moved to my buddy's site here.
# 我們那邊老是被 老是跑出去拱那個 (註︰「拱」字他發音不準)
At our site, they always ran away and snoo-
# 呃 我們 養在我們那邊老是喜歡去拱 拱那個
I mean, us, at our site, they liked going out and snout the, you know,
# 農戶的那個白菜呀
the cabbages,
# 白菜呀 包菜全部被它拱掉啦 (註︰不想太詳述是甚麼菜，又cabbage又Chinese cabbage反而欠流暢)
cabbages and other veggies of the farmers, were snouted.
# 所以我們全部
So we keep them all,
# 搞到兄弟家這邊來養
at our buddy's site here.
# 叫兄弟幫我們養
I asked my buddy to take care of them.
# 狗狗狗 狗狗狗狗狗狗
Doggy doggy, doggy doggy doggy doggy!
# 我們都那麼熟悉呀
We already know each other well enough.
# 自己人 不要咬哦
I'm your friend. Don't bite!
# 你看 這隻狗又長大啦
Look! This dog has grown bigger again.
# 以前還小的
He used to be very small.
# 你看 現在那麼大啦
Look! He's so big now.
# 這只狗很聽話的哦 那隻狗
This dog is a very good boy, this dog.
# 被兄弟拴起來啦
My buddy has put him on the tether.
# 呃 你不認識我了嗎
Eh! Can't you recognize me?
# 可以喲
Not bad
# 你看 這小豬
Look! This piggy,
# 我都不認識它啦 你看 肥成這樣
I can't even recognize it. Look! It's already that fat now.
# 變成這樣
It's that fat now.
# 小胖豬
Chubby piggy!
# 呵呵 全部掉毛了 哈哈~
Hmhm! They're all shedding hair, haha~
# 你看 上次抓過來還那麼小的
Look! It was still very small when I took it here last time.
# 現在
But now,
# 呵呵 不敢去抱啦 那麼大啦
Hmhm. I dare not take it anymore. It's so big now.
# 你看 這個 上次我們
Look! This one, when we,
# 我們 在我們那裡的時候瘦的 瘦的皮包骨一樣
us, when it was with us, it was really skinny, just like a skeleton.
# 你看 現在
Look! It's now,
# 變成這樣子啦
is already that fat now.
# 天左給它餵吃飼料 吃的好飽哇
They have fodder every day and are always stuffed with food.
# 小豬
Piggy!
# 小豬 還認不認識我
Piggy! Can you still recognize me?
# 都不理我啦
It's not answering me.
# 你看
Look!
# 這個
These are,
# 山上的野豬下來雜交出來的 (註︰他是說野豬下來的，我只好照譯)
bred from the boars coming down from the hill.
# 好尖嘴呀
They have really sharp snouts.
# 你看 它的嘴巴有點歪歪的那個
Look! This is the one whose snout is not really that straight.
# 現在都胖成這樣子啦
It's already that fat now.
# 你看 這個
Look! This is,
# 白腳的那個豬 變成這樣子啦
the pig with white feet. It's already that fat now.
# 吃太多啦
It eats too much.
# 你看 這個就是
Look! These are,
# 巴拿馬香豬 (註︰他又双叒叕說錯了，為保障我國肉品品牌和實現文化輸出的重要任務，我決定破例更正)
Bama pigs.
# 嗯 嗯 有點不像一樣
Um? Um? But they look a bit different.
# 嘴巴怎麼那麼尖
Why are their snouts so sharp?
# 這些豬都好肥啊
These pigs are all so fat,
# 胖成甚麼樣子了
that I don't even know how to describe.
# 還會喝水的哦
They can drink water here too.
# 在我們那裡
They didn't even have water,
# 水都沒得喝
when they were with us.
# 你看 這邊都被挖平啦
Look! The area here has already been flattened.
# 兄弟準備再做一個廠房
My buddy is going to build a new site here,
# 把豬養多一點
to keep more pigs.
# 好大啊 那裡
It's really big over there,
# 上千平方都有
over a thousand square metres.
# 豬看完了哦 我們準備回去啦
So that's all with the pigs. We're getting ready to go back.
# 從這裡上去 就直接回去啦
We walk up from here, then we can go back right away.
# 你看 這些白鴨好漂亮哦
Look! These white ducks are really pretty.
# 來都來啦
I'm already here,
# 裝一個鴨子回去
let me catch a duck back home.
# 這裡一個網
Here's a net.
# 趕過來 走過來
Drive them here! You come here!
# 不用趕 就這隻
No, no need. Catch this one!
# 嗯 你走過來
Um! You walk towards me.
# 慢慢的走過來
Walk towards me, slowly.
# 搞了一個七八十斤
This one is almost forty kilograms,
# 七八斤
I mean almost four kilograms
# 回去啦 回去啦
Let's go! Let's go!
# 那裡還有哦 下次再來
There are some more. I'll come again next time.
# 這個比鵝還更大的鴨子 這隻白鴨來的
This duck is even larger than a goose. It's a white duck.
# 把它放下
I put it down.
# 呃 以後這裡就是你的家了啊
Eh! This is your home from now on.
# 減一下肥
Let me put you on a diet.
# 太胖啦
You're too fat.
# 下不了口
Too fat to put into my mouth.
# 摸一下你 怎麼這樣子
I'm just petting you. What does your response mean?
# 你看 這就是你的小伙伴
Look! These are your little buddies.
# 看到沒
Can you see them?
# 把它放啦
Okay, I let it go.
# 比鵝還更大呀
It's even bigger than the geese.
# 比鵝還更大
# 太小啦 這些鴨子
They're too small, these ducks.
# 看上去這些鴨子好小呀
These ducks look really small.
# 好啦
Alright
# 讓它們這鴨子
I'm gonna leave them alone,
# 自由自在的活著
and have their worriless life here.
# 多好哇 是不是
Awesome, isn't it?
# 你們是夠幸福的啦
You guys are really privileged, you know.
# 其它鴨子全部都進啦
The other ducks are all in the,
# 進了市場
in the market,
# 變成了白條
and have become duck meat.
# 你看一下你們 是啊
Compare with yourselves, see?
# 個個都活著多好哇
You're so blessed to be all alive.
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到 就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends, ends here.
# 要等它們下蛋
I need to wait for their eggs.
# 應該差不多有蛋下啦 那麼久啦
I think they should be laying eggs very soon. They've been here long enough.